<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-06-09T10:33:56+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Cimmerian Library</title><subtitle></subtitle><author><name>Conan Liu</name></author><entry><title type="html">Misguided Intent</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/www/2022/05/04/misguidedintent.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Misguided Intent" /><published>2022-05-04T23:28:16+10:00</published><updated>2022-05-04T23:28:16+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/www/2022/05/04/misguidedintent</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/www/2022/05/04/misguidedintent.html">&lt;g&gt;
A creative piece I wrote on the destructive nature of expectations; inspired by Hedda Gabler (Ibsen).
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;style&gt;
p  {
  font-family: &quot;Baskerville&quot;, Georgia, serif;
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

The Doctor shall truly marvel at this discovery ... my discovery. The hanging gardens ...
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In two words, utterly and incomprehensibly beautiful – but the humidity is rather suffocating. However, we’ve worked so hard to get here ... I will admit, I encountered a few difficulties, but that’s over ... we were even dwindling on meat, but no more! And what a contrast this place provides ... the gardens are literally covered ... brimming ... crawling with life, and there are spontaneous arrays of colour, and the exquisite marble staircases are constricted by the most gorgeous wild flora ... 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The crystalline clear water brims over the edge of mossy drops in smooth, gentle arcs, flowing and cascading among carefully placed boulders, shimmering and looking as though they had been sprinkled with silver ...
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Even the golden statues appear so lifelike, as if real women were confined in gold ... and in them exists ...
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Dread?
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Regardless, we have worked so hard to get here, and the Doctor shoul- will be pleased. My excitement is boundless; there must be countless undocumented species to claim, and no natives to interrupt me – us. And as the sun slips below, the sky melts into a deep, bruised purple, with wisps of pink crushed between emerging stars. The constellation of Andromeda is shattered; disoriented and tarnished, proving the unplaceable nature of this place. I shudder and recite my oath. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tomorrow, I complete our task. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
---
&lt;i&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
“It’s an unknown journey. I’m … too dainty for it. And my wife’s child is coming. So please, take care.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
“I will.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
“Don’t tire yourself. Rest. Be careful. Just, let the others ... do more.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
“And what does that mean?”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
“Just ... you know ...”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
“Go on.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
“You know ... an important task is keeping the pristine journal pretty and unspoiled. We need to keep it safe. I think ...”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
“You think?”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
“You must bind it to you and focus on that. You need it. It’s your research.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
“What exactly do you mean?” 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
“The journal is the peak of your achievement … it’s your life.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
“I do not understand.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
“Well ... the rest of the team may ... have some doubts. You’re fierce, independent, assertive … you’re capable … but just with regard to you … leading … those men … given you’re a wo-”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
“Thank you. Of course!”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
“No - I meant-”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
“Farewell, Doctor.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
“Cap- Captain!”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/i&gt;
I awake from the call of my name, breathless and drenched. My purpose burns. My status among those simple men was valued but will not last – what I must complete here shall be, by the second night of the solstice. As I prepare my exploratory gear, I strain to detect any signs of life ... only the whispers of a steamed wind ... and the soughing of water nearby ... it is eerie, unnatural. It calms my mind.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
As I saunter through the secluded temples of well-aged Gods, they flaunt their extravagant engineering, unparalleled in beauty and elegance ... at least, they try to – the stone columns evidently crumbled under the weight of time, now subject to the dominion of the very nature they sought to overcome. As I continue along the stone paths, the abundance of fig trees and their broad trunks epitomise strength so effortlessly ... and their fruit is so tempting ... My daze expires when their intrusive roots trap my foot. As I recover and delve deeper into this unknown treasure of creation, I document my findings and species which men could never acquire. My journal will allow me to finally transcend … to overcome those who doubted me! It confines perfect, untouched, immaculate notes, diagrams, depictions … It will be my foundation for a non-existent culture where all of us are served superiority. It is my solution … my gains of hidden truth and power will finally gain respect for me – us! 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But as streams of melted sun tango through the thick overgrowth, my eyes begin to lose focus … my feet scream under the weight of my journey, blistered, sore … time has lost its dimension here, and has certainly escaped my conscience. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve since lost my water, and abandoned my gear. I only require the journal. Happiness flourishes in me. Finally, I feel the centre, nearing our grasp ... my grasp.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My legs tire, and my heart is weary, but the consequences of failure have been bound into the darkest depths of my mind. I must finish … I feel it so close, pulsating, waiting to be claimed! Imagine the respect … the power … I limp, but with utmost urgency! By the second night of the solstice, I shall be gone … so close … but the vegetation grows, now a hideous, vicious abomination. My shirt has since been ripped, and my skin lacerated. Yet, with apprehension now a companion to my previously established ambition … should I- may I really? My decisions falter … but how petty; turning back implies inferiority, and I shall achieve more than those men ever did; they shall suffer. Yet as vines burn my skin, my mind clouds … my journal slips … 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I reach to it, distraught … but my ankle …
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I fall, screaming. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
---
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The vegetation surrounding my body is soft, like the fur of a fawn … yet my body is numb, and my mind sways closer to the verge of oblivion … when  I shift my gaze to the navy sea above, Scorpius is blurred … and the moons …
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Panic manifests in my nerves. I glance at my wrist. Vines have constricted my movement, and dried sweat clings to my skin. Fear revitalises my senses, and my wounds burn against the poisonous grass. Trepidation chokes my thoughts, isolating my thoughts … yet I have none … only my growing hatred ... and the taste of copper plagues my mouth … as the moans of damned souls floor my ears, I recall those women … as I grip my journal, I curse those men … and the Doctor … 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Alone, I greet my fate, and my primal, misguided desires in the most deranged form …
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Rationale&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;g&gt;In his play Hedda Gabler, Henrik Ibsen focuses on the character Hedda Gabler to demonstrate how restrictions and expectations on certain genders can lead to destruction and tragedy. Notably, he subtly conveys the idea that “gender” is a construct of society and is a set of mannerisms and traits one of a specific gender must adhere to. He then shows the destructive nature these expectations have on those who do not adhere to these specific traits, and by playing Hedda with the opposite “gender” to her own, Ibsen criticises society’s restrictions on such individuals. This is emphasised through Hedda’s ‘masculine’ interests and disregarding nature (especially disregarding of womanhood and marriage) – shown in “Hedda: Well, anyhow, I still have one thing to kill time with. Tesman: Thank heavens for that! But what is it, Hedda? Eh? Hedda: My pistols, Jorgen.” (Ibsen, 1890, pg. 295); “Brack: No, no. That wasn’t what I was thinking of either. But suppose now there comes what, in rather solemn language, is called a serious claim on you, one full of responsibility? A new claim, little Madam Hedda. Hedda: Be quiet! You’ll never see anything of the kind.” (Ibsen, 1890, pg. 306, Act II); and “Tesman: Yes, but have you noticed how plump she’s grown, and how well she is? How much she’s filled out on our travels? Hedda: Oh, be quiet - !” (Ibsen, 1890, pg. 275, Act I). 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
While Hedda understands her true desires, she is completely conscious of societal expectations and therefore fears the pursuit of them. She ultimately feels trapped, unable to express her masculinity or femininity, to the point of suicide as a means of escape. This highlights Ibsen’s criticism of society and how its constricting construct of “gender” can prohibit one’s expression of themselves, eventually leading to tragedy. Throughout the play, Ibsen also hints that these constructs are dominated by men in a patriarchal society; the majority of opportunities are in the favour of men, regardless of their gender performativity, as seen with Tesman’s ability to earn (though he is also portrayed as an opposite “gender”, especially acting as a duality with Hedda) and Brack’s freedom (even though portrayed in a similar manner to Hedda). Hence her wrong gender role is the sole limiter of her actions. The theme of confinement and its danger is emphasised by Ibsen’s use of setting; Hedda never leaves the house and is forever confined, helping criticise the dangers of social restriction around gender. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the creative piece, similar to Hedda Gabler, the explorer is portrayed as the wrong “gender” and demonstrates traits that are stereotypically masculine (“… You’re fierce, independent, assertive”). However, even though she leads an exploratory team, her real gender, portrayed as the wrong gender role, ultimately confines her and her academic growth. It is this confinement that ultimately leads to others doubting her, which results in destruction and madness in the form of her hatred toward all men – this is reinforced through her confusion of equality with superiority over men, as seen in “… It will be my foundation for a non-existent culture where all of us are served superiority”. Notably, society’s construct of “gender” is dominated by the perspectives of men. This is criticised in the response, and is seen with the Doctor (a male) forcing the journal, a symbol of femininity, upon the explorer – “ ... an important task is keeping the pristine journal pretty and unspoiled … I think ... you must bind it to you and focus on that. You need it” (the symbol is feminine with the use of “pristine” and “pretty”, feminine adjectives). 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The consequences of a patriarchal construct of “gender” and the enforcement of rigid gender identity is shown by the actions of the Doctor; even though he is a male, he is portrayed in the wrong gender role – as shown by his timid and uncertain nature in dialogue, as well as “It’s an unknown journey. I’m … too dainty for it. And my wife’s child is coming. So please, take care.” - he still succeeds. Hence the explorer’s wrong gender role becomes known as the sole factor prohibiting her growth. This restriction and expectation of gender leads to her hatred toward all men. Society’s patriarchal construction of “gender” being the sole limiter on the explorer and the cause of her tragedy is emphasised when the journal physically leads to the downfall of the explorer (because she is so fixated upon the restrictions forced upon her by the Doctor) – “… my journal slips … I reach to it, distraught … but my ankle … I fall, screaming”. Setting is used in a manner similar to Ibsen again – the explorer never leaves the garden, helping emphasise the message of how social restriction around gender can lead to tragedy. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The similar techniques and approaches in the play and in the response ultimately show and criticise how restrictions and expectations around gender can lead to destruction.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Bibliography:
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Ibsen, H., 1961. Hedda Gabler and Other Plays. England: Penguin Books Ltd.
&lt;/g&gt;


&lt;/g&gt;</content><author><name>Conan Liu</name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="www" /><summary type="html">A creative piece I wrote on the destructive nature of expectations; inspired by Hedda Gabler (Ibsen).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">the Interlude</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/www/2022/05/04/theinterlude.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="the Interlude" /><published>2022-05-04T23:28:16+10:00</published><updated>2022-05-04T23:28:16+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/www/2022/05/04/theinterlude</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/www/2022/05/04/theinterlude.html">&lt;g&gt;
A creative piece I wrote on perspectives; inspired by William Blake&apos;s poems.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;style&gt;
p  {
  font-family: &quot;Baskerville&quot;, Georgia, serif;
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As the sun melted into the horizon, dying shards of sunlight glided through the veiled windows. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Dust permeated the room, slithering, gently, to the rhythm of the breeze. A rose petal fell.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
I sat, slowly, poured a glass, and drank. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Nearly one full harvesting cycle had passed. Probably the last. The stover outside had nearly fully dried. In a way, they looked like odd, propped up banana peels. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
I leaned into my chair. Bananas. They were difficult to propagate this year. It was the climate, and the rain, and the rotting roots. The last model of Martian breeders probably couldn’t handle it. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
The doorbell rang. I straightened up.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“Noah!” 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
I spat out my warm whiskey, hiding it. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“Yeah!” 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
I shuffled to the door and swung it open. Alarmed, I staggered back. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
He smiled, looming in the doorframe. “Noah! It’s been too long!”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
I blinked. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“Dusty as ever out here. And God is good?” He cackled. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
I stood still, startled. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“Ahem. Anyway.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
I grimaced.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“Will you… allow me in?”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“Oh. Of course.” I stepped aside. “How rude of me. It’s been too long. Please, come in.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Lamech sauntered in, wrinkled his nose, and squinted, observing the space. “This place is… nostalgic.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“In a good way?”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Lamech inspected the ceiling. “… Perhaps. Can we sit?”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
I sat, gesturing to Lamech. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“I’ve come for a reason.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“Why? Please.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“I’ve come into possession of the plantation GA21.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
I sat, slowly.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“I know you used to own it, and yes, The Company seized it, but don’t worry! It’s mine now! I got it back! They gave it to me!”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“How did you get it back?”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“Look. Just know I got it back… and the stash was still intact.” 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
I leaned into my chair, scrutinising his leather duffel. “Why did you sail all the way here? Tell me. Your plantations are huge trips away and now… you’ve got our stash?”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“Well, the trip was shortened. You could say that the travel time across the sea was… split for me. But yes. It has all the plans, the notes, everything! The original copies, at least.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“I am aware it contains our belongings.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“Well, I’ve brought some.” 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Lamech stood, filing through his duffel. Stained, creased files spilled onto the table. Ripped documents I had drowned in the darkest confines of my memories floated to the surface. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“Here.” 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Lamech smiled, wistfully. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
He handed me my journal. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
The 17th Day of the Second Month, 2049: 
&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;
‘God saw everything that He had made, and behold, it was very good’. I think I can finally agree with Him today. To my surprise, Lamech and I have been offered generous funding from The Company for our new research project, and we’ve hired some of the best engineers we know to help us solve the food scarcity issues ravaging the Earth. Even though I’ve engineered my farm to function, the climate simply doesn’t allow it elsewhere. Lamech and his plantation almost perished, but I revived it, just in time. Thank God for that. And now The City is advancing onto the moon in their Lunar projects! Excitingly, they’re taking some of my crops up there in a hibernation pod in preparation for our 3-year deadline on our crop breeding machines. It is truly a blessing to be alive right now. Contributing to industrialisation, progressing humanity into the future, and relishing in the Glory with my colleague, my truest friend, my dearest mentor, Lamech: it is truly a blessing. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
The 17th Day of the Second Month, 2052: 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Progressing into the future while reflecting with maturity and avoiding the weak excuse is a rare commodity among the Earth’s population. Clearly. They had Lunar missions, but swiftly realised they could not actually produce food there, sustainably. It was a living Hell.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
But we’ve done it today. Our culminations of failure, with the incubation of optimism; we’ve done it! Not unlike those before us, we stand on the shoulders of giants. But we’ve found the missing gene. We’ve finally synthesised what I call ‘breeders’. These beautiful, organic greenhouses. And with the gene now quantised, we can finally grow almost any crop in almost any environment. The gene itself is a combination of many DNA structures and allows for adaptability in the propagation of plants. The sheer number of varieties we have broken down in plants, the sheer number of climates we have traversed in the last 3 years, the hardship! We have truly made the greatest technological leap since the invention of coffee. And now, we can physically grow coffee on the moon. Finally. In the most convenient timing possible, we have saved humanity of this dying Earth. Now, we industrialise the moon! The once baron and unachievable, now the tamed and habitable. And from the saved Earth, the new White House. And from there, who knows. But I do know I have saved us all, from the deathly gallows of overpopulation, and the deathly battle against malnourishment. Truly, thank God for His blessings!&lt;/i&gt;   
&lt;br /&gt; 
I dammed my tears. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Lamech clapped. “Remember? You saved everyone! You found the link in the breeder mechanism! Noah, remember this. You led the way onto Mars with the first generation of breeders. You made the trip possible. You got the ships working. And now look at these new crops… wait, let me get it up. Here, let me show you!”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
A hologram materialised, showing fields covered with synthetic roofing. Luscious, abundant vegetations framed the red, Martian sky. Lamech toggled the images, rambling about the revolutionary crops, but I already knew. I used to grow those crops with him.  
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“And now look, we’re making bounds like it’s 2059! Remember that year, Noah? There were so many innovations… we compacted the solar panels, the Benz started to float, The Company launched my favourite multivitamin drink, which, hey, also use your crops B29 in the ingredients, and Goddamn it I nearly forgot! The latest model of Eve came out! And you know what? I earned my money back on that purchase!”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
I scowled. “And how’s the latest now?”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Lamech sighed, closing his eyes. “Heavenly. She’s an angel. Seriously. I think I’m at the lab with Luluwa every… third? Every second night? Hell, during the harvesting periods on Mars I think she’s helping me finish my job every night!”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“The lab?” I frowned. There were no labs in the plantation district. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“My lab.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“Your lab?”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Lamech stood. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“… Your shortened trips, the acquisition of our old farm… You work fo-”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“I work for The Society.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Realisation dawned on me. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
I pointed at Lamech, feebly, like it would stop him. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“… It was you… you were the one! The one who sacrificed my work! You sold my work to them! I-” 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“And what, Noah? They sponsored our research! For three, long years! Then they physically produced the breeders in mass! Only they could have processed so many! Who else had enough power at the time? And then they bought my dying plantation! They compensated me! They gifted me salvation, and new life!”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
I started crying.  
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“I know you think you’re the sole owner of your work, your ideas. And now that you know I sold your ideas for a huge sum, that I’m some worm who cut you off, but… but industrialisation needs power! Like a rose… needs soil! And they had the power we needed! Manual power, processing power, societal power. And now look. They got us onto Mars! They’re The Society now! Wouldn’t it feel good to bathe in such power? With Gods among men?” 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Lamech clasped my shoulder. “Join us and help industrialise Saturn, Noah.” 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
I laughed, bitterly crying. “And how would I do that, Lamech?”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
In my moment of pure weakness, my former friend only attempted the insane.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“… Sell your farming network.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“… Where would I go? Besides my memories and my half bottle of whiskey it’s the one place, the one belonging I have left, and now you’re trying to lull me into your sick illusion after you caved in and sold yours to the people who stole everything we had pioneered together?”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Lamech sighed. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“You stole my discovery and left me to die! Those who you worship… they do this, they steal! Do you see, Lamech? Those who hold such power… it’s simply power stolen from the individuals! No. No, Lamech. No! I won’t sell it so you can expand The City!” 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“… Your sins disappoint me. And repeat after me: it’s the Society.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“No… It’s theft.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Lamech shook his head. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Outside, the fields burned. Flames, like Satan’s fingers, lit the darkness.   
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
“You’re one of the smartest I’ve ever met, Noah. But sometimes, the best thing a rose can do for us… is to die.” 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Then I heard it – that slightly ethereal, mechanical purr. Like some robotic demon. I knew… it was them: The Company. They’d come, one day, and take the little I had left. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Lamech loaded his gun.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
So, I sat, fleetingly, wondering… have I become the rose? Lucid, but immovable. Beautiful, but transient all the same, in my destiny to just… wither away?  
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;g&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Rationale&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In his poems “Jerusalem”, “The Chimney Sweeper” (from both Songs of Innocence and Songs of Experience) and “The Sick Rose”, Blake focuses on symbolism and creating dualities to convey the destructive potential of industrialisation. Notably, he subtly conveys how the oppressive nature of industrialisation is the true crux of its destruction, symbolised by the once “holy” England now overcome by “dark Satanic mills” (Blake, 1804). He then communicates that such oppression leads to the deathly dehumanisation of the already powerless within society - children who were originally “locked up in coffins” (Blake, 1789) and freed by “angels” to “shine in the sun” (Blake, 1789) are ultimately sold into slavery, “clothed … in the clothes of death” (Blake, 1794), and eventually diminished into “little black things among the snow” (Blake, 1794). 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
The destructive nature of industrialisation, especially regarding the powerless, is further emphasised by the dualities of free will and crushing inevitability; children become chimney sweepers before they can even “cry … notes of woe” (Blake, 1794) and although they are “happy and dance and sing” (Blake, 1794), they are destined to, themselves, contribute to what they fear most: a “heaven of … misery”. Blake’s underlying duality of religious beliefs and failed salvation furthers the concept of industrialisation being a destructive construct. By criticising churches as “dark Satanic mills” (Blake, 1804), he communicates religion only misleads the helpless individuals within society to further fuel the very industrialisation that oppresses them, by believing “if all [the children] do their duty they need not fear harm” (Blake, 1794). As industrialisation is furthered, the ignorance elicited within society toward the helpless is doubly emphasised by parents who abandon their children, excusing themselves “to praise God”. Ultimately, Blake conveys industrialism with the destructive potential of an “invisible worm”, a worm that forcefully destroys the “life” of the powerless within society: the “sick” “roses” (Blake, 1794). 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
In the narrative, the destructive potential of industrialisation on individuals is explored through two perspectives. Like Blake who creates dualities in his poems, the perspectives are explored many years apart and oppose each other in all regards. In the journal recount, we see an individual, Noah, continually praise God and relish in “industrialisation”. The consistent symbolism of life, whether saving or creating it, conveys the perspective that industrialisation benefits the world, having “saved humanity” of a “dying Earth”. Noah believes industrialisation “progresses society into the future” and upon receiving the opportunity to “contribute”, he gladly accepts with his “truest friend” and “mentor”, Lamech, while thanking “God for His blessings”. Such a view is reiterated by Lamech in the present, who credits industrialisation for multiple “innovations”, and Noah for “saving everyone”, helping humanity colonise interplanetary systems. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
However, the perspective mirroring that of Blake’s is conveyed in the present – the destructive potential of industrialisation is, like in Blake’s poems, shown to diminish the life of the most powerless within society. Because industrialisation has helped humanity, it now holds immense value. By extension, those who industrialise ultimately gain “power”. However, with such power, helpless individuals who do not comply are oppressed, as shown by an abandoned Noah who loses all character. Notably, Lamech, who was once a mentor of Noah (like the parents in Blake’s poems), betrays Noah twice to further industrialisation. This betrayal is highlighted through biblical intertextuality and the subversion of biblical allusion; though Noah helped send everyone onto Mars with his “ark”, he is the one considered to be “sinning” with alcohol rather than Lamech, who engages in sexual activity. Lamech’s ignorance toward individual suffering is fuelled by capitalistic industrialisation, being “compensated” with such “salvation” to the extent of forgetting Noah “used to grow those crops with him [Lamech]” and being indoctrinated to say: “repeat after me: it’s the Society”. Like a “worm”, he indifferently states “sometimes, the best thing a rose can do for us… is to die” - the sense of inevitability and childish weakness present in Noah’s consequent questioning of fate to “wither away” reinforces the oppression individuals face from industrialisation.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Hence, the similar techniques and approaches used in Blake’s poems and the narrative ultimately explore the destructive potential of industrialisation.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Bibliography:
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
ArkEncounter. 2021. Noah’s Family. [ONLINE] Available at: https://arkencounter.com/noah/family/. [Accessed 14 September 2021].
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Blake, W. 1789. ‘The Chimney Sweeper’ [ONLINE]. Available at: https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/54684/jerusalem-and-did-those-feet-in-ancient-time. [Accessed 14 September 2021].
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Blake, W. 1794. ‘The Chimney Sweeper’ [ONLINE]. Available at: https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/43653/the-chimney-sweeper-a-little-black-thing-among-the-snow. [Accessed 14 September 2021].
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Blake, W. 1794. ‘The Sick Rose’ [ONLINE]. Available at: https://poets.org/poem/sick-rose. [Accessed 14 September 2021].
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Blake, W. 1804. ‘Jerusalem’ [ONLINE]. Available at: https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/54684/jerusalem-and-did-those-feet-in-ancient-time. [Accessed 14 September 2021].
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
GotQuestions. 2021. Who was Lamech in the Bible?. [ONLINE] Available at: https://www.gotquestions.org/Lamech-in-the-Bible.html. [Accessed 14 September 2021].
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Tropicamango. 2021. How not to kill your banana tree. [ONLINE] Available at: http://www.tropicamango.com/banana.html. [Accessed 14 September 2021].
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Wikipedia. 2021. Genesis flood narrative. [ONLINE] Available at: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Genesis_flood_narrative#:~:text=Noah%20entered%20the%20Ark%20in,cubits%2C%20and%20all%20earth%2Dbased. [Accessed 14 September 2021].
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Wikipedia. 2021. Luluwa. [ONLINE] Available at: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luluwa#:~:text=Luluwa%20(also%20Aclima)%20according%20to,human%20who%20was%20born%20naturally.. [Accessed 14 September 2021].


&lt;/g&gt;






&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/g&gt;</content><author><name>Conan Liu</name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="www" /><summary type="html">A creative piece I wrote on perspectives; inspired by William Blake&apos;s poems. As the sun melted into the horizon, dying shards of sunlight glided through the veiled windows. Dust permeated the room, slithering, gently, to the rhythm of the breeze. A rose petal fell. I sat, slowly, poured a glass, and drank. Nearly one full harvesting cycle had passed. Probably the last. The stover outside had nearly fully dried. In a way, they looked like odd, propped up banana peels. I leaned into my chair. Bananas. They were difficult to propagate this year. It was the climate, and the rain, and the rotting roots. The last model of Martian breeders probably couldn’t handle it. The doorbell rang. I straightened up. “Noah!” I spat out my warm whiskey, hiding it. “Yeah!” I shuffled to the door and swung it open. Alarmed, I staggered back. He smiled, looming in the doorframe. “Noah! It’s been too long!” I blinked. “Dusty as ever out here. And God is good?” He cackled. I stood still, startled. “Ahem. Anyway.” I grimaced. “Will you… allow me in?” “Oh. Of course.” I stepped aside. “How rude of me. It’s been too long. Please, come in.” Lamech sauntered in, wrinkled his nose, and squinted, observing the space. “This place is… nostalgic.” “In a good way?” Lamech inspected the ceiling. “… Perhaps. Can we sit?” I sat, gesturing to Lamech. “I’ve come for a reason.” “Why? Please.” “I’ve come into possession of the plantation GA21.” I sat, slowly. “I know you used to own it, and yes, The Company seized it, but don’t worry! It’s mine now! I got it back! They gave it to me!” “How did you get it back?” “Look. Just know I got it back… and the stash was still intact.” I leaned into my chair, scrutinising his leather duffel. “Why did you sail all the way here? Tell me. Your plantations are huge trips away and now… you’ve got our stash?” “Well, the trip was shortened. You could say that the travel time across the sea was… split for me. But yes. It has all the plans, the notes, everything! The original copies, at least.” “I am aware it contains our belongings.” “Well, I’ve brought some.” Lamech stood, filing through his duffel. Stained, creased files spilled onto the table. Ripped documents I had drowned in the darkest confines of my memories floated to the surface. “Here.” Lamech smiled, wistfully. He handed me my journal. The 17th Day of the Second Month, 2049: ‘God saw everything that He had made, and behold, it was very good’. I think I can finally agree with Him today. To my surprise, Lamech and I have been offered generous funding from The Company for our new research project, and we’ve hired some of the best engineers we know to help us solve the food scarcity issues ravaging the Earth. Even though I’ve engineered my farm to function, the climate simply doesn’t allow it elsewhere. Lamech and his plantation almost perished, but I revived it, just in time. Thank God for that. And now The City is advancing onto the moon in their Lunar projects! Excitingly, they’re taking some of my crops up there in a hibernation pod in preparation for our 3-year deadline on our crop breeding machines. It is truly a blessing to be alive right now. Contributing to industrialisation, progressing humanity into the future, and relishing in the Glory with my colleague, my truest friend, my dearest mentor, Lamech: it is truly a blessing. The 17th Day of the Second Month, 2052: Progressing into the future while reflecting with maturity and avoiding the weak excuse is a rare commodity among the Earth’s population. Clearly. They had Lunar missions, but swiftly realised they could not actually produce food there, sustainably. It was a living Hell. But we’ve done it today. Our culminations of failure, with the incubation of optimism; we’ve done it! Not unlike those before us, we stand on the shoulders of giants. But we’ve found the missing gene. We’ve finally synthesised what I call ‘breeders’. These beautiful, organic greenhouses. And with the gene now quantised, we can finally grow almost any crop in almost any environment. The gene itself is a combination of many DNA structures and allows for adaptability in the propagation of plants. The sheer number of varieties we have broken down in plants, the sheer number of climates we have traversed in the last 3 years, the hardship! We have truly made the greatest technological leap since the invention of coffee. And now, we can physically grow coffee on the moon. Finally. In the most convenient timing possible, we have saved humanity of this dying Earth. Now, we industrialise the moon! The once baron and unachievable, now the tamed and habitable. And from the saved Earth, the new White House. And from there, who knows. But I do know I have saved us all, from the deathly gallows of overpopulation, and the deathly battle against malnourishment. Truly, thank God for His blessings! I dammed my tears. Lamech clapped. “Remember? You saved everyone! You found the link in the breeder mechanism! Noah, remember this. You led the way onto Mars with the first generation of breeders. You made the trip possible. You got the ships working. And now look at these new crops… wait, let me get it up. Here, let me show you!” A hologram materialised, showing fields covered with synthetic roofing. Luscious, abundant vegetations framed the red, Martian sky. Lamech toggled the images, rambling about the revolutionary crops, but I already knew. I used to grow those crops with him. “And now look, we’re making bounds like it’s 2059! Remember that year, Noah? There were so many innovations… we compacted the solar panels, the Benz started to float, The Company launched my favourite multivitamin drink, which, hey, also use your crops B29 in the ingredients, and Goddamn it I nearly forgot! The latest model of Eve came out! And you know what? I earned my money back on that purchase!” I scowled. “And how’s the latest now?” Lamech sighed, closing his eyes. “Heavenly. She’s an angel. Seriously. I think I’m at the lab with Luluwa every… third? Every second night? Hell, during the harvesting periods on Mars I think she’s helping me finish my job every night!” “The lab?” I frowned. There were no labs in the plantation district. “My lab.” “Your lab?” Lamech stood. “… Your shortened trips, the acquisition of our old farm… You work fo-” “I work for The Society.” Realisation dawned on me. I pointed at Lamech, feebly, like it would stop him. “… It was you… you were the one! The one who sacrificed my work! You sold my work to them! I-” “And what, Noah? They sponsored our research! For three, long years! Then they physically produced the breeders in mass! Only they could have processed so many! Who else had enough power at the time? And then they bought my dying plantation! They compensated me! They gifted me salvation, and new life!” I started crying. “I know you think you’re the sole owner of your work, your ideas. And now that you know I sold your ideas for a huge sum, that I’m some worm who cut you off, but… but industrialisation needs power! Like a rose… needs soil! And they had the power we needed! Manual power, processing power, societal power. And now look. They got us onto Mars! They’re The Society now! Wouldn’t it feel good to bathe in such power? With Gods among men?” Lamech clasped my shoulder. “Join us and help industrialise Saturn, Noah.” I laughed, bitterly crying. “And how would I do that, Lamech?” In my moment of pure weakness, my former friend only attempted the insane. “… Sell your farming network.” “… Where would I go? Besides my memories and my half bottle of whiskey it’s the one place, the one belonging I have left, and now you’re trying to lull me into your sick illusion after you caved in and sold yours to the people who stole everything we had pioneered together?” Lamech sighed. “You stole my discovery and left me to die! Those who you worship… they do this, they steal! Do you see, Lamech? Those who hold such power… it’s simply power stolen from the individuals! No. No, Lamech. No! I won’t sell it so you can expand The City!” “… Your sins disappoint me. And repeat after me: it’s the Society.” “No… It’s theft.” Lamech shook his head. Outside, the fields burned. Flames, like Satan’s fingers, lit the darkness. “You’re one of the smartest I’ve ever met, Noah. But sometimes, the best thing a rose can do for us… is to die.” Then I heard it – that slightly ethereal, mechanical purr. Like some robotic demon. I knew… it was them: The Company. They’d come, one day, and take the little I had left. Lamech loaded his gun. So, I sat, fleetingly, wondering… have I become the rose? Lucid, but immovable. Beautiful, but transient all the same, in my destiny to just… wither away? Rationale In his poems “Jerusalem”, “The Chimney Sweeper” (from both Songs of Innocence and Songs of Experience) and “The Sick Rose”, Blake focuses on symbolism and creating dualities to convey the destructive potential of industrialisation. Notably, he subtly conveys how the oppressive nature of industrialisation is the true crux of its destruction, symbolised by the once “holy” England now overcome by “dark Satanic mills” (Blake, 1804). He then communicates that such oppression leads to the deathly dehumanisation of the already powerless within society - children who were originally “locked up in coffins” (Blake, 1789) and freed by “angels” to “shine in the sun” (Blake, 1789) are ultimately sold into slavery, “clothed … in the clothes of death” (Blake, 1794), and eventually diminished into “little black things among the snow” (Blake, 1794). The destructive nature of industrialisation, especially regarding the powerless, is further emphasised by the dualities of free will and crushing inevitability; children become chimney sweepers before they can even “cry … notes of woe” (Blake, 1794) and although they are “happy and dance and sing” (Blake, 1794), they are destined to, themselves, contribute to what they fear most: a “heaven of … misery”. Blake’s underlying duality of religious beliefs and failed salvation furthers the concept of industrialisation being a destructive construct. By criticising churches as “dark Satanic mills” (Blake, 1804), he communicates religion only misleads the helpless individuals within society to further fuel the very industrialisation that oppresses them, by believing “if all [the children] do their duty they need not fear harm” (Blake, 1794). As industrialisation is furthered, the ignorance elicited within society toward the helpless is doubly emphasised by parents who abandon their children, excusing themselves “to praise God”. Ultimately, Blake conveys industrialism with the destructive potential of an “invisible worm”, a worm that forcefully destroys the “life” of the powerless within society: the “sick” “roses” (Blake, 1794). In the narrative, the destructive potential of industrialisation on individuals is explored through two perspectives. Like Blake who creates dualities in his poems, the perspectives are explored many years apart and oppose each other in all regards. In the journal recount, we see an individual, Noah, continually praise God and relish in “industrialisation”. The consistent symbolism of life, whether saving or creating it, conveys the perspective that industrialisation benefits the world, having “saved humanity” of a “dying Earth”. Noah believes industrialisation “progresses society into the future” and upon receiving the opportunity to “contribute”, he gladly accepts with his “truest friend” and “mentor”, Lamech, while thanking “God for His blessings”. Such a view is reiterated by Lamech in the present, who credits industrialisation for multiple “innovations”, and Noah for “saving everyone”, helping humanity colonise interplanetary systems. However, the perspective mirroring that of Blake’s is conveyed in the present – the destructive potential of industrialisation is, like in Blake’s poems, shown to diminish the life of the most powerless within society. Because industrialisation has helped humanity, it now holds immense value. By extension, those who industrialise ultimately gain “power”. However, with such power, helpless individuals who do not comply are oppressed, as shown by an abandoned Noah who loses all character. Notably, Lamech, who was once a mentor of Noah (like the parents in Blake’s poems), betrays Noah twice to further industrialisation. This betrayal is highlighted through biblical intertextuality and the subversion of biblical allusion; though Noah helped send everyone onto Mars with his “ark”, he is the one considered to be “sinning” with alcohol rather than Lamech, who engages in sexual activity. Lamech’s ignorance toward individual suffering is fuelled by capitalistic industrialisation, being “compensated” with such “salvation” to the extent of forgetting Noah “used to grow those crops with him [Lamech]” and being indoctrinated to say: “repeat after me: it’s the Society”. Like a “worm”, he indifferently states “sometimes, the best thing a rose can do for us… is to die” - the sense of inevitability and childish weakness present in Noah’s consequent questioning of fate to “wither away” reinforces the oppression individuals face from industrialisation. Hence, the similar techniques and approaches used in Blake’s poems and the narrative ultimately explore the destructive potential of industrialisation. Bibliography: ArkEncounter. 2021. Noah’s Family. [ONLINE] Available at: https://arkencounter.com/noah/family/. [Accessed 14 September 2021]. Blake, W. 1789. ‘The Chimney Sweeper’ [ONLINE]. Available at: https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/54684/jerusalem-and-did-those-feet-in-ancient-time. [Accessed 14 September 2021]. Blake, W. 1794. ‘The Chimney Sweeper’ [ONLINE]. Available at: https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/43653/the-chimney-sweeper-a-little-black-thing-among-the-snow. [Accessed 14 September 2021]. Blake, W. 1794. ‘The Sick Rose’ [ONLINE]. Available at: https://poets.org/poem/sick-rose. [Accessed 14 September 2021]. Blake, W. 1804. ‘Jerusalem’ [ONLINE]. Available at: https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/54684/jerusalem-and-did-those-feet-in-ancient-time. [Accessed 14 September 2021]. GotQuestions. 2021. Who was Lamech in the Bible?. [ONLINE] Available at: https://www.gotquestions.org/Lamech-in-the-Bible.html. [Accessed 14 September 2021]. Tropicamango. 2021. How not to kill your banana tree. [ONLINE] Available at: http://www.tropicamango.com/banana.html. [Accessed 14 September 2021]. Wikipedia. 2021. Genesis flood narrative. [ONLINE] Available at: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Genesis_flood_narrative#:~:text=Noah%20entered%20the%20Ark%20in,cubits%2C%20and%20all%20earth%2Dbased. [Accessed 14 September 2021]. Wikipedia. 2021. Luluwa. [ONLINE] Available at: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luluwa#:~:text=Luluwa%20(also%20Aclima)%20according%20to,human%20who%20was%20born%20naturally.. [Accessed 14 September 2021].</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Extracting code chunks from RSweave/Rmd file</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/datascience/ds/2022/02/11/extracting-code-from-Rsweave.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Extracting code chunks from RSweave/Rmd file" /><published>2022-02-11T00:28:16+11:00</published><updated>2022-02-11T00:28:16+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/datascience/ds/2022/02/11/extracting-code-from-Rsweave</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/datascience/ds/2022/02/11/extracting-code-from-Rsweave.html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when I write a report in RSweave, I will have a normal .R file on the side to test out code that I will need in the report. However, I also lose discipline at times and I end up completing all code within the RSweave file anyway. At times when I just want to upload the code to Github, I need a quick way to extract all code chunks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;&lt;b&gt;Step 1: set working directory to where the base file is&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot; data-lang=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;getwd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;setwd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;&lt;b&gt;Step 2: set object as file name&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot; data-lang=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;yourfilename.Rnw&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NB: the base file name must be unique within the working directory. So in the case of RSweave files, where (as it uses LaTeX) after generating a report a bunch of other files with the same base name (but different extensions) are produced, you will need to rename the RSweave file to something completely different and unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;&lt;b&gt;Step 3: see below commands&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For files operating under knitr, use “purl”. Otherwise use “Stangle” for RSweave variants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot; data-lang=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;knitr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;purl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot; data-lang=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Stangle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Conan Liu</name></author><category term="datascience" /><category term="ds" /><summary type="html">Why?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Melbourne Housing Market Analysis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/datascience/ds/2022/01/12/Report.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Melbourne Housing Market Analysis" /><published>2022-01-12T00:28:16+11:00</published><updated>2022-01-12T00:28:16+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/datascience/ds/2022/01/12/Report</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/datascience/ds/2022/01/12/Report.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a self-guided project where I analysed a Melbourne housing market dataset from Kaggle. Credit to Tony Pino for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was conducted completely in RStudio, with the help of RSweave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;centre&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1TMzfM_B8470IlZ6tHNOCPsiuF2CFVg8e/preview&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;900px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/centre&gt;</content><author><name>Conan Liu</name></author><category term="datascience" /><category term="ds" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On being a good leader</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/growth/2021/10/16/on-being-a-good-leader.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On being a good leader" /><published>2021-10-16T00:28:16+11:00</published><updated>2021-10-16T00:28:16+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/growth/2021/10/16/on-being-a-good-leader</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/growth/2021/10/16/on-being-a-good-leader.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe loyalty and gratitude are two of the most important, fundamental traits that every person aspiring to be a leader should aim to develop. I don’t think I can think of any other traits from which all issues (professionally or otherwise) boil down to. And the key message lies within “aim to develop”. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Loyalty&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Loyalty is definitely an important one. But loyalty to many evokes the image of comraderie, a marriage, a connection to someone. But loyalty to a person is a huge caveat. Loyalty to a person too often spawns beauracracy, which with its derivative politics only causes the downfall of great teams and kills (competitive) collaboration. Loyalty should be to your word, a set of values, an organisation’s purpose, a vision, mission, or other frameworks that help you become a better person and make better decisions. Because being loyal to a person could mean when they are wrong, you also inevitably agree. However, healthy challenges in a relationship are necessary, and opposition is really the truest form of friendship. When you are loyal to a set of values, it also reflects in character, and you are less likely to shave the truth, and more likely to say the same thing to everyone, regardless of any outcomes. Loyalty leads to character. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Gratitude&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Gratitude is equally, if not (arguably) more important, than loyalty. In my opinion, gratitude is the single trait that any issue can boil down to, especially in relationships and personal development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Developing these traits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Like any skill, developing loyalty and gratitude takes a conscious effort, time and patience. In many senses, developing these is a process that never ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember when I first entered Year 11 (2020, about 16-17 years old), we had an opening assembly, and at some point the chaplain of the school came out to deliver her speech. I will admit: I was zoning out. However at some point I started listening and I am grateful I did, because her story about two wolves was powerful, to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To summarise, without getting into the details of a biblical allegory: within each of us lies two wolves - there is a dark one, and a light one. You may feed either wolf. It is up to you to decide which wolf you want to feed through your actions and thoughts. Do you want to feed the one who is jealous, scheming, and evil? Or the one who is compassionate, kind, and honest?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved her story because loyalty and gratitude are trained. You must make conscious efforts every day to stregnthen your loyalty and gratitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to develop these skills. Personally, I will list something I am thankful for, something I am grateful for, something I am hopeful for, and something I am sorry for, every single day. I do think there is a subtle difference between “thankful” and “grateful”. I do like the definition &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a src=&quot;https://liveboldandbloom.com/07/values/grateful-vs-thankful#:~:text=You%20can%20exhibit%20your%20thanks,in%20both%20fable%20and%20psalm.&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Listing such things helps to develop the aspect of reflection that builds gratitude, and enforcing such a habit every day will, over time, mould you to become more appreciative of literally every good thing in your life, no matter how small or large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflecting about things you are sorry for every day is not to be taken to the extreme. Simply reflecting on where you could have displayed a better attitude or approach to someone, or people, is powerful. And it can especially&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surround yourself. Bitter poeple - bitter you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;actively externally reflect&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Food for the soul&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
“It’s harder to be kind than to be clever. It’s the difference between gifts and choices. Cleverness is a gift. Kindness is a choice.” - Jeff Bezos&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To know even one life has breathed easier because you have lived, this is to have succeeded.” – Ralph Waldo Emerson&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Conan Liu</name></author><category term="growth" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Integrating Github with RStudio project</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/datascience/ds/2021/07/24/Github-integration-with-R-copy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Integrating Github with RStudio project" /><published>2021-07-24T23:28:16+10:00</published><updated>2021-07-24T23:28:16+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/datascience/ds/2021/07/24/Github-integration-with-R%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/datascience/ds/2021/07/24/Github-integration-with-R-copy.html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By integrating an RStudio project with Github, you can directly push changes using Git. This is extremely convenient and is actually what I used to build a website for my club, completely within R itself. And, to my observation, you can create a whole project, sync it to a new repo and when you commit+push all your new files, you may upload more than 100 files at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;&lt;b&gt;Step 1: create a new Github repository&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go create a new repository. The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;readme.md&lt;/code&gt; file is optional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;&lt;b&gt;Step 2: enable Git in RStudio&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Open your project in RStudio and follow Tools -&amp;gt; Version Control -&amp;gt; Project Setup.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Click on the SVN/Git tab. Select Git as the version control system. It will ask you to initialise a new Git repo and restart RStudio.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After Rstudio reopens, confirm that there is a Git tab in the &lt;b&gt;environment&lt;b&gt; (where you view all your objects) pane (top right by default).&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;&lt;b&gt;Step 3: synchronise with a Github repository&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In RStudio, click on the terminal tab and start a new terminal session. Then enter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-terminal&quot; data-lang=&quot;terminal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sets your terminal directory to home default. Then add next locations step wise. For me, I had my project on my desktop, and its name was “club”. So, I would enter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-terminal&quot; data-lang=&quot;terminal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;cd Desktop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-terminal&quot; data-lang=&quot;terminal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;cd Desktop/club&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, set an origin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-terminal&quot; data-lang=&quot;terminal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;git remote add origin https://github.com/yourUSERname/REPOname.git&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you added optional files into your repo, such as the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;readme.md&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;license.md&lt;/code&gt; file, enter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-terminal&quot; data-lang=&quot;terminal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;git pull origin master&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To pull them from the otherwise empty repository. If you didn’t add any files, no need for this step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, enter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-terminal&quot; data-lang=&quot;terminal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;git push -u origin master&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you should be ready to commit files to the repository. Along the way you may have needed to sign in to your Github account and entered some keychains if on a Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;&lt;b&gt;Step 4: push files to Github from RStudio&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the environment pane, click on the Git tab and then click Commit. This will open a window where you can track files you made changes to. Tick all boxes for files you want to push. If you are using Github to build a website, and you have lots of files changing at once after building it to see how it looks, you can tick one box, go CMD+A and tick all of them. Write a commit message in the adjacent field and then click an up arrow to push.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Conan Liu</name></author><category term="datascience" /><category term="ds" /><summary type="html">Why?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fourier Transform Report</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/academics/academic/2021/04/11/fourier.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fourier Transform Report" /><published>2021-04-11T23:28:16+10:00</published><updated>2021-04-11T23:28:16+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/academics/academic/2021/04/11/fourier</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/academics/academic/2021/04/11/fourier.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This was an assignment where we had to detail an application of complex numbers. I spent around three days trying to find a great application and landed on the fourier transform from signal analysis videos! The report also includes a wonderful, real world analysis example where a time series is broken into individual sine waves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All images that are unreferenced (all but one), including the graphs and spiral images, were all created using functions in R. These were quite finnicky, to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ggplot2 was used to plot the cartesian planes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The report was created using RSweave/LaTeX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted the formatting is sometimes… off. Looking back on this I probably would have tried to fix the LaTeX formatting somehow… the pictures sometimes overflow onto the next page leaving huge chunks of white. Too difficult at the time, but for the next project formatting will definitely be a major goal toward the end. Even mathematical working is too long at times, so I need to find a way to present these things better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;centre&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1lArDzTNNePDyorZPIuKdKlXkjoq_jhvg/preview&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;900px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/centre&gt;</content><author><name>Conan Liu</name></author><category term="academics" /><category term="academic" /><summary type="html">This was an assignment where we had to detail an application of complex numbers. I spent around three days trying to find a great application and landed on the fourier transform from signal analysis videos! The report also includes a wonderful, real world analysis example where a time series is broken into individual sine waves.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Neural Networks Textbook</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/academics/academic/2020/12/03/textbook.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Neural Networks Textbook" /><published>2020-12-03T00:28:16+11:00</published><updated>2020-12-03T00:28:16+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/academics/academic/2020/12/03/textbook</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/academics/academic/2020/12/03/textbook.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This was an assignment where we had to design a textbook chapter on an application of matrices. I chose neural networks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also had to design some problems with worked solutions at the end of the chapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The textbook was designed in Adobe Illustrator. All diagrams are handmade, also in Illustrator. I used Helvetica Neue for the font in the neural network diagrams, but looking back on this in retrospect, I think another, slightly bolder typeface would have helped the readability (especially with those super/subscript numbers!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;centre&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1DuMyCPDXu_kqkTncv7q_Ln9pO_g0TMnV/preview&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;900px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/centre&gt;</content><author><name>Conan Liu</name></author><category term="academics" /><category term="academic" /><summary type="html">This was an assignment where we had to design a textbook chapter on an application of matrices. I chose neural networks!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Separating posts by category with Liquid</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/datascience/ds/2020/12/02/liquid-tagging.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Separating posts by category with Liquid" /><published>2020-12-02T00:28:16+11:00</published><updated>2020-12-02T00:28:16+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/datascience/ds/2020/12/02/liquid-tagging</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/datascience/ds/2020/12/02/liquid-tagging.html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;b&gt;Separating and organinising blog posts by their categories&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using liquid it is possible to directly loop all posts for a certain category or tag:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-liquid&quot; data-lang=&quot;liquid&quot;&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;site.categories[&apos;category&apos;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;limit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;n&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;
    &amp;lt;a href=&quot;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;endfor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;n&lt;/code&gt; is the (maximum) number of posts that show. It’s the same code for tags; just replace &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;site.categories[&apos;news&apos;]&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;site.tags[&apos;news&apos;]&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Conan Liu</name></author><category term="datascience" /><category term="ds" /><summary type="html">Separating and organinising blog posts by their categories</summary></entry></feed>